<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Conquering Quoridor</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2014-02-14T17:54:26+00:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Chris Hughes</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>hughes.c.i@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baby Steps]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/articles/baby-steps/"/>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/articles/baby-steps</id>
  <published>2014-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hughes</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hughes.c.i@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So whilst not much has happened on this blog for the past two weeks I have been spending a little time here and there on the project. Unfortunately I’ve fallen into the trap of putting off updating the blog until I’ve made ‘meaningful progress’, whatever that is! Well instead of waiting for that to happen I want to discuss my current thoughts on how I plan to progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;splitting-the-problem-up&quot;&gt;Splitting the problem up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that when I’m thinking about Quoridor my thoughts will bounce around trying to solve everything at once. Whilst that can be fun and produces loads of ideas it doesn’t get you very far. The obvious solution is to break the problem down and then focus on the smaller problems. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest and most important split is to separate the playing of the game from the AI. In theory with a team of clever people I believe you could work simultaneously on these two aspects, if you agreed on a communication protocol. Now that does sound pretty cool but unfortunately I am a team of one so it’s not an option. Even though when I started this I was most interested in the AI aspect I’ve decided to begin with building the game for the simple reason that I have no idea how i would do it the other way round!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually many good reasons to start with building a playable game:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a better idea of what is needed and so will be a good place to refresh my Javascript skill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provides some good visual milestones which will be good for motivation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will force me to understand the finer points of the rules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll need something for my AI to interact with&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With a bit of extracurricular work I should be able to play against people online!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-the-game&quot;&gt;Building the game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now i have focused in on building the game I’m busy researching all the different aspects involved, which will be the focus of my next post, hopefully not too long from now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/articles/baby-steps/&quot;&gt;Baby Steps&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Hughes at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Conquering Quoridor&lt;/a&gt; on February 13, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quest to Conquer!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/articles/a-quest-to-conquer/"/>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/articles/a-quest-to-conquer</id>
  <published>2014-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hughes</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hughes.c.i@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So i’ve finally got my act together and decided to set myself a challenge. Not being content with only taking on the stress of regularly updating a blog, i’ve also decided to pick a problem that I’m not even sure I can do! But I am hoping it will provide a number of interesting problems covering a variety of areas that I can at least have a go at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenge&quot;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the challenge? Simply put, i’m going to beat a board game. Specifically, I’m going to solve a board game. Even more specifically, I’m going to solve the board game &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quoridor&quot;&gt;Quoridor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you not familiar with Quoridor, it is a 2 or 4 player strategy game where you race through self made mazes which develop as the game is played. Sounds good right? Here’s a video explaining how to play (plus a little on strategy too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/KcuBheYqdjs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;!----&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve seen how to play Quoridor, what does solving it mean? Well i’m already at a point where i don’t know enough to adequately answer that, but from the research i’ve done so far it can best be summed up as being able to identify the perfect move in any given situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;NB. If any mathemiticians are cringing at that definition please bear in mind that I have only just begun and I have much to learn&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, solving the game will probably be far beyond my reach, but that doesn’t mean I shouldn’t try! If all I end up with is a kick-ass AI opponent I won’t be too upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;am-i-qualified-to-actually-do-this&quot;&gt;Am I qualified to actually do this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I spent my time studying maths at university. Recently I came across some maths that would have been no problem to 20 year old me, yet I found myself staring blankly at the page (what the hell is a dot product anyway?). Realising I was well into my mathematical decline was one of the main motivations for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since university i’ve been lucky enough to hang out with some people doing great things in the web development world (check out what &lt;a href=&quot;http://benjaminbenben.com&quot;&gt;Ben Foxall&lt;/a&gt; is getting up to). Through these contacts i’ve dabbled in a bit of Javascript which is what I intend to do most of my work on this project in, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think you can all see that if anything I am over-qualified for this job! More realistically I’m an enthusiastic amateur looking forward to learning all the aspects involved in this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;havent-other-people-already-done-this&quot;&gt;Haven’t other people already done this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! A quick google search will turn up a few online games plus an &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=air.QuoridorBoardGame&quot;&gt;Android app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t dishearten me, if anything it provides me with necessary competition! Any AI that I create can be directly competed against theirs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can build the number one quoridor engine in the world I would be so happy. The ten other guys who’ve ever tried can suck it!&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/articles/a-quest-to-conquer/&quot;&gt;A Quest to Conquer!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Hughes at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Conquering Quoridor&lt;/a&gt; on January 28, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
